We have learned about singly linked list.
Now let's learn about doubly linked list a link.
Atlas D. et al.
Contains an extract pointer typically called previous pointer, together with next pointer and data
which are there in Link his list.
So this is the double link at list.
This is the note of W. linked list.
So this note contains data.
And next, as the single list singly linked list.
But here we have an extra point which points to the previous.
OK.
And underneath it will become memory access for according to this course.
So when you say memory, access, memory address, it is underneath that point.
The note and we have a previous point and next pointer and the date that that it is contained inside
the note.
So in order to make a note for link it list and see it's about struct note and data and the pointer
to the next struct node pointer and struct node to their previous.
In Java, the last note contained in data note of the affair or object of note class called the previous
object of note class called next, and the constructor is the same as the singular link, unless this
is the link at best we can.
We have this Dublin and could list that contains three link three nodes.
The first one at the address 1024, the second address 2024, and the third address is at three thousand
twenty four.
OK, so we have a had we have that the nodes and you see guys that w flash.
So this is the doubly link.
And lest it refer to the previous and the previous one refers to this node as its next by making do
flashes two arrows.
So you see guys how the arrows are functions one from the previous and one from the next.
OK.
Now, creating a link at lest we start by creating struck note had middle and last I will create three
notes one for the head, one for the middle and one for the last.
And in say we need to allocate their memory by calling had equal to malloc size of struck note.
And the medal the same and the last the C, in order to put a data inside these Dublin and kit list,
we've put had Flash or this Arrow data equal to 100 had middle the data the same at Java Medal data
or middle dash at this last data equal to 200 and the last equal to 300.
This is what we have created.
We have created three nodes head, middle and less.
We have put that inside the first 100, the second 200 and 300 and the last as data now.
How to link them in order to link them.
We put had previous equal to none.
So we've put we say that the had the previous of the head would be none.
So the point that to the previous.
Not before the head is not, and the head to the next is equal to me.
OK, so the first note is referring as previous to now and the next to the mid.
Consider the middle note, the middle note.
But as previous as it had so that previous note before to the middle is head and the next of the middle
pointing to that last note and the last that previous is is referring and referencing to the middle,
while the last dot next or the next reference to the last is equal to none.
This is what we have created.
We have created doubly linked list with this doubly arrows referring to the head as null as previous
and next to it the reference to the middle.
And we have.
Referenced the middle.
Previous to it as 1024, the memory editors of head and the next of its three thousand twenty four,
which is the last and the last known address and the last note contains the previous and linked the
previous as 2024.
And the last is equal to the last, the DOT next is referencing that they're not OK.
So in next video, we will learn about printing.